

linkedin.com/in/ben-liu github.com/ben196888 (+66) 825 811 373 ben196888@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Ben Liu is focusing on full-stack web apps developing these 5 years. He worked in JavaScript with ReactJS for 3.5 years and NodeJS for 2 years. He is always passionate about new technology and likes to learn new ideas from developer events and open source projects. He is not only an avid problem solver but also a good autodidact who is keen on more than one solution.

# **SKILLS**

Skills TypeScript, JavaScript, Golang, Docker, C#

Libraries ReactJS, Redux, RxJS, NodeJS

Databases Firebase, Mongo, PostgreSQL, MSSQL

Tools Elasticsearch, Kafka

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Agoda, Bangkok, Thailand

Full-Stack Software Engineer

- Design the dynamic
- Led 5 Devs and 1
- Introduce new client widgets for Agoda to win China market.

#### Predictive Hire, Melbourne, Australia

Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2019

Software Engineer

- Reduced 600% CI/CD run time by decoupling micro-services in same integration test rate.
- Led 4 Devs and 1 DevOps to start migrating monolithic API services to micro-services.
- Guided 2 data specialists to process and ship 1.5 GB data to report customers every month.

#### Tabcorp, Melbourne, Australia

Jan. 2017 - Sep. 2018

Sep. 2019 - Present

Developer

- Led 3 Devs and 1 DevOps to build an API service for 5000 transactions per min in 4 weeks.
- Solved 3rd party API issues across the Ops team and Devs team on production in one day.
- Reduced DOM unit tests 3500% execution time by replacing headless chrome with JSDOM.
- Increased unit tests coverage rate from 75% to higher than 95% by adding 100+ test cases.
- Resolved the browser crashed issue by throttling when receiving 150+/s data stream.
- Unblocked bottleneck to render 500% more transactions per second by queueing the stream.

#### HopebayTech, Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2014 - Oct. 2016

Software Engineer

- Designed and developed an internal human resource system to replace the paperworks of 100+ employees.
- Created 5 continuous integration pipelines for 5 web apps and 2 cross-compiling build systems.

### **EDUCATION**

#### National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

Jul. 2009 - Feb. 2014

Bachelor of Science degree in Mathematics